Thank you so much for joining us.
We have an internal debate in staff of what's going to be the more popular of the two services.
It seems like the morning people are, you guys are awesome.
We don't, you know, I don't encourage gambling,
but our new executive pastor did send an email to our staff asking for them to guess
how many people are going to be at each service.
And he did offer for me to buy the winner lunch.
So I'm like passively gambling.
And, you know, apparently that's what we're doing here at Canvas Community Church.
If you are new or newer here, we do say we are a church full of real people
with real lives learning to follow Jesus in a difficult cultural moment.
And we would say that Easter and the resurrection of Jesus is at the center of everything for us.
This is the biggest day of the year.
But in reality, it's something that we celebrate every week.
The reason that we meet together on Sunday mornings is because that marks the day that Jesus rose from the dead.
It marks the day of new creation.
And I've been thinking a lot about how to explain that in the most simplest of terms
now that I have a three-year-old asking me questions.
How do you explain that the garden is being restored, that new creation is here and present
now that Jesus has crushed the head of the serpent when there is still darkness?
Like Amy prayed, many of you are coming into this place with difficulty and pain,
and we are singing celebratory songs about the resurrection.
And yet for you, you have not yet experienced the resurrection.
And as I drove here this morning for the sunrise service, for those really morning people,
I just, I watched the sun kind of coming over the mountains on the way from my house,
and I just saw a light spreading.
And yet I looked towards the sunrise, and I saw a light spreading,
and I looked in the opposite direction, and there was still darkness in many places.
I think that's such a helpful way for us to think about new creation dawning
and Christ crushing the head of the serpent and life of the garden spreading.
It is spreading, and it will continue to spread.
And one day the Scripture says that we will no longer need the sun
because the presence of the Lord will be our light.
But until that day comes, many of you in here are in the shadows.
You are experiencing darkness, and I do not want that to go unseen.
And I do not want you to hear a trite message where we just ignore the pain and brokenness of this world
because we do not.
But we do not grieve as people without hope.
So I hope to communicate that more in full with the rest of my time this morning.
Let's go ahead and pray for our time.
Father in heaven, you are so good.
We thank you for the reality of a garden being renewed through the faithful one, Jesus Christ.
And God, we sometimes experience resurrection life
and sometimes experience the chaos and destruction of life outside the garden.
And yet we know in the midst of both of those experiences,
you are present, you are faithful, and that you love us.
Sin broke a lot of things and messed a lot of things up,
but what it never interrupted was your love for us.
Even as you are in tears placing Adam and Eve outside of the garden,
you clothe them and you promise to send them a savior.
Your love has never run out and it never will run out.
And if we're in here and we do not yet feel that,
we have not yet experienced that, I pray that we would.
And God, for those of us who have experienced it
and yet are doubting it or struggling or wrestling with whether it's true,
God, give us renewed hope.
In Jesus' name I pray, amen.
We're gonna start with a little bit of crowd participation.
Before we get to the main part,
just so that we know either
our older generation in the room
or the holiest people in the room,
raise your hand if you never had a video game console in your house.
Holy, holy.
Okay, so from now,
let's go, raise your hand if I,
once I named the first video game console
that you had in your house.
Who was the Atari?
Who had Atari first?
Okay, awesome.
You're old and holy.
I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
Nintendo, the original Nintendo.
We got some Nintendo people.
Okay.
How about the Sega Genesis?
All right, all right.
My parents raised their hand over there.
That means that was for me.
The original PlayStation.
All right, now we're getting younger and less holy.
Okay.
The Xbox.
Who was an Xbox person?
I got some Xbox people in the room.
Now, now, are there any,
are there any really young people in here
that would have meant the Nintendo Switch
was like your first game console?
Okay, we got some people here.
Thank you for the young people in the room.
I remember one of my most vivid memories
was a Christmas Eve
where my parents had saved up
and surprised my brother and I
with the original PlayStation,
which was really a shock for us.
We didn't, I didn't grow up with a lot of money.
And so this was a huge surprise.
I was really excited about it.
But because we didn't have a lot of money,
there's this thing now,
some of you younger people in the room,
you're not gonna know what this is.
There's this thing called demo discs
that the game came with.
Yeah, my PlayStation came with some demo discs.
And because my parents sacrificially
worked really hard to get us this game,
we spent the first few months playing the demo discs.
We had the console, but not really the games.
I had to wait until the next big holiday
or until I could convince my grandparents
to buy me a game.
So we loved it.
Had this original PlayStation with some demo discs.
And one of the ones I remember most vividly
was a game by the name of Spyro the Dragon.
Anybody?
Okay.
Spyro the Dragon was one of the demo discs.
And I played it on repeat.
You kind of flew this little dragon around.
You could blow fire at enemies.
There he is right there.
You could collect coins
that would help you along the journey.
It was fun at first,
but the demo was contained
to a very small portion of the map.
And there really was no storyline.
And there wasn't much that you could do at all
except for fly around and blow fire,
which was fun for about a month,
I will admit.
But then it got boring.
There was not a whole lot there.
I quickly lost interest.
And then eventually we got the real game
and I was a bit skeptical
because I'd been so burnt out by the demo
that I wasn't really sure
that Spyro the Dragon was for me.
And then eventually I gave it a chance
and I was blown away
by how much deeper the real game was to the demo.
There was a storyline that you could follow.
There were hidden trails that you could go along.
There was so much more.
There was different landscapes and hidden paths
and deeper challenges
and a whole story was unfolding.
And this morning,
as we look at John's account of the resurrection,
I wanna make the argument
that I think for many of us,
especially from the gospel of John,
if we've grown up around
the kind of evangelical culture of the day,
we've been given what I would say
is a demo version of the message
of the gospel of Jesus.
It's not untrue.
It's not a part of the message,
but it's shrunken down
and it's missing its entirety.
It's a message that's particularly
about your individual soul
going to heaven when you die.
Again, not untrue,
but it's a demo version
of what John really wants to get across
in his gospel story.
And today from the gospel of John,
I wanna look at a much more full
and beautiful story
of what Jesus actually accomplished
through his life,
death, resurrection, and ascension.
One that isn't limited
to one aspect of our future reality,
but one that infiltrates all creation
and our entire lives.
One that impacts how we live
and breathe and move on a daily basis.
How we interact with God's good world gone wrong
and how we treat one another
in the midst of our suffering
and our tears and our fear
and our regrets.
Easter is the culmination of a story
that has been unfolding
since the beginning.
The New Testament
isn't some unexpected add-on
to a story that began with God's creation.
It is the fulfillment
of what we read
on the first pages of Scripture
when God put Adam and Eve
in a good garden.
And what we're gonna find here
as we get to John chapter 20,
if you wanna follow along with me,
we're gonna read from there eventually,
is that John goes out of his way.
He's the one gospel author
that goes out of his way
to make sure that you know
that the resurrection happened in a garden.
And he's not doing this on accident.
What he is arguing
is that the message of Jesus,
the resurrection,
is not just about eternal salvation,
but it is about new creation bursting forth.
It is about Jesus restoring God's good world
and making the garden of Eden
spread back through creation.
It happens one person at a time
through the power of the Holy Spirit,
but it is spreading.
That's why I've titled my message this morning
From Garden to Garden,
How the Resurrection of Jesus Restores Creation.
And again, with the rest of our time,
I wanna explore some subtle clues from John's gospel
that show us the true story of Jesus
isn't primarily about forgiveness,
but about new creation.
If you have your notes,
you can follow along with me on the back.
I'm gonna start here by looking at how John
revisits the beginning of the story of Scripture
and the beginning of his gospel.
In Genesis chapter one, verses one through three,
we read,
In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.
The earth was formless and empty
and darkness covered the deep waters.
Then God said,
Let there be light.
And there was light.
So from the first pages of Scripture,
we have God speaking words
that bring light out of darkness.
And John begins his gospel
almost in the exact same way.
In John chapter one, verses one through five,
it says,
In the beginning.
Sound familiar?
John's not reinventing the wheel here.
He wants us to have the garden in mind
when he starts his message of the gospel of Jesus.
In the beginning, the word already existed.
The word was with God and the word was God.
God created everything through him
and nothing was created except through him.
The word gave life to everything that was created
and his life brought light to everyone.
So for John, Jesus is the visible expression
of God's spoken word,
bringing light into the darkness of broken creation.
John's claim from the beginning of his book
isn't just Jesus coming to save our souls for eternity,
but God is restarting his good world
through Jesus crushing the head of the serpent.
He's restoring the goodness of the garden of Eden.
He came to undo the lies of the enemy
that lead us away from God,
lies that lead us to selfishness,
dehumanization, destruction.
This is where sin comes into the world
because we believe the lies of the enemy.
We believe that the way of the enemy will lead to life
when in reality, it leads to death and destruction.
And Jesus is shining a light on a new way of being human.
John's gospel is filled with clues
that he's primarily talking about new creation
and not about just where we go when we die.
But because I don't have all mourning,
we're not gonna trace all of John's clues.
We're just gonna skip ahead
to the crucifixion and resurrection.
In the first section, we see these similarities
where John kind of compares the beginning of his letter
to the beginning of the book of Genesis.
And as we move along, we'll see some more comparisons
and also some ways that they contrast one another.
He moves on to focus on the brokenness of creation.
In Genesis chapter one, verse 27, it says,
in the image of God, he created them,
male and female, he created them.
So in Genesis, we have God creating Adam and Eve
and declaring that these humans were made in his image.
They are representations of all of humanity moving forward.
And when they fail, we all fail.
And then you have this really weird line
that John shares in John chapter 19, verse five,
where Pilate brings out Jesus to the crowd.
And he says, look, here is the man.
Isn't that weird phrasing?
You ever been reading through the Scriptures
and something, there's like a weird way of saying something.
You're like, the translators must've really messed up there.
If you see something that looks weird like that,
zoom in on it a little bit and figure out why it is weird.
I think what we have here is we have,
in Genesis, we have God bringing out Adam and Eve and saying,
this is humanity created in my image.
This is what goodness looks like.
And then in John, we have Pilate.
We have the empire proclaiming Jesus as the true image bearer
without knowing what they're doing.
Pilate is proclaiming Jesus as the new Adam,
representing all of humanity
and going to the cross on our behalf,
taking death and restoring dominion in the garden.
It moves on in Genesis chapter three
as the curse comes onto creation after humanity sins.
It says, God says,
This is death entering God's good world,
focused on thorns and the sweat of our brow
and fear and the brokenness of other people
warring against one another.
And in John 19, we see the soldiers wove a crown of thorns
and put it on his head and the crowd chanted,
crucify him, crucify him.
John wants us to have in mind creation
as we see what Jesus is doing on our behalf.
He is the new image of God doing in a desert
what Adam and Eve could not do in the garden.
Jesus is taking on the curse of death.
And overcoming it.
In Genesis chapter two,
we read that in the middle of the garden,
God placed the tree of life
and the tree of the knowledge of good and evil.
These trees were intended for life
and flourishing a mutually good
and beneficial relationship between humans and God.
But it was the tree in the middle of the garden
that ultimately led to our death and chaos.
And then John is the only gospel author
that goes out of his way to describe Jesus's cross
as being in the middle of the crucifixion.
In John 19,
then Pilate turned Jesus over to him to be crucified.
They took Jesus away, carrying the cross by himself.
He went to the place called the place of skull.
So we've got a tree in the middle of the garden
and now we have a tree in the middle of the desert.
There they nailed him to the cross.
Two others were crucified with him,
one on either side with Jesus in the middle.
John uses the same Greek word
that the Septuagint translates,
the tree in the middle of the garden.
He wants us to have the garden in mind.
He wants us to see that when Adam and Eve failed
in the midst of the garden with a tree,
Jesus succeeded in the midst of the desert on a cross.
Jesus steps into the world of Genesis 3
outside of the garden.
His ministry culminates in him being stripped naked,
beaten and killed for a crime
that he did not commit on a tree
in the middle of a place called the skull.
Jesus steps outside of the garden
to overcome the lies of the enemy that we believe,
that got us removed from the garden.
And he did this to open up a door for us
to experience the garden life again.
This is not a demo version of the gospel.
John does not just want you to think about
your individual sins being forgiven.
He wants you to think about
all of creation being restored.
Sometimes we shrink what Jesus did down so much
that we miss the grand scheme
of all that God is doing through Jesus.
And I am preaching better than you guys are responding.
For John, the crucifixion is the culmination
of a world and rebellion.
This is as bad as it can get.
Humanity is crucifying God on a cross
in the middle of the desert.
For John, this is as bad as it can get
and everything is about to turn around.
Jesus is putting an end to the lies of the enemy
that have led humanity down this path.
He is crushing the head of the serpent
and providing a new way for humans to relate to God.
He's kick-starting new creation.
Self-giving love is greater than selfish violence and greed.
And then we zoom in on the resurrection account.
I'm just gonna read the whole thing
because I think we should do that on Easter
and then we'll come back and grab a couple of highlights.
There's more than I have time to cover.
And so I would encourage you this week
if you wanna read John 20 and 21
with the Garden of Eden in your mind
and try and see some of the ways
in which John wants us to think about
Jesus kick-starting new creation.
Wait, I might have gotten ahead on my notes.
I did.
I got ahead.
We're not gonna read that yet.
So what happens when you guys don't respond well enough?
I try and skip pages of my notes.
All right, the turning point.
As Jesus is being crucified,
in this section, John clearly wants us to see
how Christ's work of new creation
mirrors God's work in the original creation account.
On the sixth day in Genesis chapter one,
God looked over all that he had made
and he saw that it was very good,
marking the sixth day, Friday in the week.
In John chapter 19,
Jesus finishes the work necessary for new creation
on the sixth day.
It is finished, he says.
John says it was the day of preparation.
John goes out of his way to let us know
the days and the times of things happening.
And then on the seventh day,
when God had finished all of his good creation
in the garden, he rested from all his work.
In John chapter 19,
the place of crucifixion was near a garden
where there was a new tomb, never used before.
And so before, because it was the day of preparation
for the Jewish Passover
and since the tomb was close at hand,
they laid Jesus there.
Jesus, who is God,
completed the work of new creation on the sixth day
and rested in the tomb on the seventh.
This is new creation coming about
through the sacrificial love,
through the life, death, burial,
and resurrection of Jesus.
The gospel of John is a literary masterpiece.
He puts the image of the Garden of Eden
in our minds in chapter one.
And the entire story leads us back to a garden
to show us that Jesus is launching new creation.
This is so much better than the demo mode
of the gospel that many of us have in our minds
when we think about what Jesus did.
Light is bursting through the darkness
and we are being invited into a totally new way
of being human.
Now, let's get to the resurrection account.
We've got new creation being finished on the sixth day,
Jesus resting on the seventh day,
and John goes out of his way
to mention that this is the first day of new creation.
This is why we gather together on Sunday morning.
Sunday marks the first day of new creation.
Now, on the first day of the week,
Mary Magdalene came to the tomb early
while it was still dark.
On the first day of creation,
light is coming through the darkness.
And she saw the stone had been taken away from the tomb,
so she ran and went to Simon Peter
and the other disciple,
the one whom Jesus loved.
John has a really interesting way
of talking about himself and Peter
that I don't have time to get into.
And he said to them,
they have taken the Lord out of the tomb
and we do not know where they have laid him.
So Peter went out with the other disciple.
They were going towards the tomb.
Both of them were running together,
but the other disciple outran Peter
and reached the tomb first.
Stooping to look in,
he saw the linen clothes lying there,
but he did not go in.
Then Simon Peter came following him
and went into the tomb.
He saw the linen clothes lying there
and the face cloth,
which had been on Jesus' head,
not lying with the linen clothes,
but folded up in its place.
Then the other disciple
who had reached the tomb first,
again, John, chill,
also went in and he saw and believed,
for as yet they did not understand the Scripture
that he must rise from the dead.
Then the disciples went back to their homes.
But Mary stood weeping outside the tomb
and she wept.
She stood and looked into the tomb.
She saw two angels in white sitting
where the body of Jesus had laid,
one at the head and one at the feet.
They said to her,
woman, why are you weeping?
She said to them,
they have taken away my Lord
and I do not know where they have laid him.
Having said this,
she turned around and she saw Jesus,
but she did not know it was him.
Jesus said to her,
woman, why are you weeping?
Whom are you seeking?
Supposing him to be the gardener,
she said to him,
sir, if you have carried him away,
tell me where you have laid him
and I will take him away.
Jesus said to her,
Mary.
She turned and said to him in Aramaic,
Rabboni, which means teacher.
Jesus said to her,
do not cling to me
for I have not yet ascended to the father,
but go to my brothers and say to them,
I am ascending to my father
and to your father,
my God and your God.
Mary Magdalene went and announced to the disciples,
I have seen the Lord
and that he said these things to her.
On the evening of that day,
the first day of new creation,
the doors being locked
where the disciples were for fear of the Jews,
Jesus came and stood among them
and he said to them,
peace be with you.
When he said this,
he showed them his hands and his side.
Then the disciples were glad
when they saw the Lord.
Jesus said to them again,
peace be with you
as the father has sent me,
even so I am sending you.
And when he had said this,
he breathed on them
and said to them,
receive the Holy Spirit.
So again,
with the garden imagery in our minds,
John goes out of his way to say,
this is the first day of new creation
and it is in darkness
and the word of God,
light is spreading out from Jesus
on the first day of new creation.
light is dawning,
hope has come.
When the curse happens in the garden,
you see human beings hiding from God.
And in this account,
we see Mary searching for God.
New creation is dawning.
Human beings are beginning to catch a vision
for what life could look like
in relationship with God and one another.
I got a deep cut for those of you
that grew up in Sunday school.
We got time for it real quick?
All right,
you notice we had two angels
on either side of where Jesus laid?
So the deep cut is,
in the Old Testament,
we have the description of the tabernacle,
which all theologians agree
is a working model of Eden,
the Garden of Eden,
wherever Israel would go.
In the midst of Israel,
it's God's presence dwelling with his people
just like he did in the garden.
And at the center of the tabernacle,
you have a place called the mercy seat
inside the Holy of Holies.
And what is on the mercy seat?
You have an angel on either side of the mercy seat
where the presence of God
dwells in the midst of his people.
And when John says here,
there's an angel on either side
of where Jesus laid,
he's not just giving details that don't matter.
He's asking the people of God
who know the story of God
to know that the presence of God
was dwelling there
and he has risen from the dead
and he is here now
and new creation is dawning.
This small working model of creation
that can only be with Israel
and this tent is no longer matters
because God is spreading the garden
all throughout the rest of the world.
First day, humans go looking for God.
God's presence is there.
And I love in Genesis,
we have God planting the garden.
And in John 20,
we have Jesus mistaken for the gardener.
What a small detail that John has here
as almost to say like you,
mistaken as the gardener,
but no, he actually is the gardener.
He is bringing the garden of Eden
back to this broken world.
When we pray on earth as it is in heaven,
it's not just this spiritual reality
that we hope to be true in the future.
It is an invitation for us to participate in God,
bringing new creation through his people,
his new creation.
And the last thing that happened
on the first day of new creation
is Jesus breathes on the disciples
the breath of new life.
Just as in Genesis,
God breathed life into Adam.
It says he breathed on Adam,
the breath of life.
The last thing that John goes out of his way
to say that happened
on the first day of new creation
is Jesus breathed on his disciples.
Have you ever read that
and been like, that's weird?
Somebody just, my friend,
if Corey just walked up to me
and breathed on me,
I'd be like, dude, get away from me.
It's not like there's some first century thing
we don't know about
where people were just gone
breathing on each other.
No, John is going out of his way
to say that Jesus is God
and he is bringing about new creation
and he is breathing new life
into the new human beings
who will trust him,
who will follow him,
who will say,
the enemy has been crushed.
I no longer have to believe the lies
that lead to fear, dehumanization
and warring against one another.
I can now live open-handedly
with my abundance.
I can love God
with all of my heart, soul, mind and strength.
And I can love my neighbor as myself.
This is how the garden spreads
from here until Jesus returns.
Us, new humans
with the power of the Holy Spirit
living inside of us,
loving the Lord our God
with our heart, soul, mind and strength
and loving our neighbor as ourself.
For John,
the good news of Jesus
is that the garden
is beginning again
and human beings
are invited to participate.
Fellowship with God
is restored
and partnership
with one another
is now a realistic possibility.
This version of the gospel
blows the demo mode
out of the water.
It's not just about forgiveness
of sins
or future destination.
It's about here
and now.
Every breath we take
is an invitation
to partner with God
to bring about his good world
gone wrong.
The gospel
isn't just about eternal life
but abundant life now.
You guys are getting there.
I appreciate it.
So like I said earlier,
I quickly burn out
on the demo mode of Spyro
and I was a bit skeptical
that the real game was for me.
And I can't help but think
that there are some of us
in the room today
that have grown up
with kind of a demo version
of the gospel.
Jesus died for your sins.
Ask him into your heart.
You go to heaven when you die.
Again, not untrue
but just one facet
of all that Jesus is doing
and wants to do
in your life here and now.
And I can't help but think
that there are people
in the room this morning
who might be thinking
like me
that Spyro isn't for me.
You might be thinking,
yeah, this gospel thing,
this Jesus raising
from the dead thing,
it sounds great.
It's nice for the people
that it's nice for
but it's not for me.
And if that's you,
if you're in here,
if you're skeptical,
if you have reasons
for not believing
or not wanting to believe
or maybe you want to believe
and you just can't get over
the hurdles,
the obstacles,
the darkness in your life.
I love how John ends his gospel,
how he resolves the story.
He resolves his story
with Jesus going
to three different individuals
who have three very real reasons
for not wanting to believe.
And Jesus speaks their name.
So as we begin
to close this morning,
I just want to look
at these three accounts
and ask you to consider
if you find yourself
in one of these situations,
is it possible?
Is it possible that Jesus
wants to speak your name
this morning?
Is it possible
that the obstacles
that you have allowed
to keep you
from believing in Jesus
are obstacles
that he has already overcome?
In John chapter 20,
Jesus first goes to a woman
who is crippled
with grief and suffering.
Her name's Mary.
She stood,
we already read it,
she stood weeping
outside the tomb.
She can't find him.
She's talking to angels
and doesn't seem
to be that freaked out about it.
And she turns around,
she sees somebody
that she thinks is a gardener
and it's Jesus
and he says,
woman, why are you weeping?
Whom are you seeking?
Supposing him
to be the gardener,
she said to him,
sir, if you've carried him away,
tell me where you have laid him
and I will take him away.
And Jesus said to her,
Mary.
And immediately her name
snapped her out of it.
She no longer supposes him
to be the gardener,
but she says,
Rabboni,
my teacher, my Lord.
And God,
and Jesus goes out of his way
for the first time
in the gospel.
He refers to God
as my father
and your father,
my God
and your God.
New creation
is breaking through.
Mary is distraught.
Everything she thought
she knew about life
seems to be coming unraveled.
She'd seen Jesus
do miraculous things
and possible things
in her life
and in the life
of those around her
and yet she finds herself
this morning,
early in the morning,
confused and heartbroken,
filled with sorrow
as she takes a long walk
to prepare the body
of the one
whom she thought
was the Messiah.
And I can't help
but think many of us
in the room
have had similar experiences.
the way that you thought
your life would go.
It hasn't worked out.
You've had sickness,
death, infertility,
broken relationships,
on and on we could go.
You've heard
the message of Jesus
and the message of hope
and you've wanted it
to be true
and yet in your own life
you have not experienced it.
Maybe you've seen
others experience it
but you have not yet
found it.
You've prayed
and expected God
to show up
and he seems dead
and all you have left
like Mary are tears.
And as I prepared
this message this morning
I just,
I can't help
but think that
for many of you
Jesus somewhere
deep inside of you
is whispering your name.
He is not shaming you
for your tears
or for your angry prayers
or for your lack
of prayers.
He is calling you
by name.
He sees your sorrow
and he sees your pain
and he is not absent
from it.
He is in the middle of it.
And although he might
not make it all go away
the way that you
want him to,
right here and right now
he is resurrecting
your story
and he is giving you
a hope for the future.
And if Jesus truly
rose from the dead
then everything
is different.
Light is penetrating darkness.
It might take longer
than we hope
and it might look different
than we expected
but he can be trusted.
Not only does he go
to Mary and her sorrow
but he goes to Thomas
and his intellectual doubt
in verse 24.
Thomas one of the disciples
who wasn't there
when Jesus first showed up
and said peace be with you
and did the weird
breathe on you guys thing.
Thomas one of the twelve
called the twins
was not with them
when Jesus came
so the other disciples
told him we have seen
the Lord
but he said to them
unless I see his hands
the mark of the nails
the place where his fingers
are
and the place
his hands on the side
I will never believe.
Eight days later
his disciples
were inside again
and Thomas was with them.
Although the doors
were locked
Jesus came
and stood among them
and said peace be with you.
Then he said to Thomas
put your finger here
and see my hands
put out your hand
and place it on my side
do not disbelieve
but believe.
Thomas answered him
my Lord
and my God.
Jesus said to him
have you believed
because you have seen me?
Blessed are those
who have seen
who have not yet seen
and have still
believed.
I mean can anybody
blame Thomas
for not believing
that Jesus rose
from the dead?
This is an incredible claim
that goes against
everything he has ever
known or expected
and Jesus is probably
standing over my shoulder
being like
Ryan actually
he saw Lazarus
raised from the dead
so not everything
that he could have
right?
Like we can imagine
Jesus being like
come on Thomas
you were there dude
you've been with me
for three years
you've heard me prophesy
talk about resurrection
you saw me raise
Lazarus from the dead
come on
seriously?
Is that what we see
Jesus doing?
Of course not.
He comes to Thomas
in the midst of his doubt
and shows him
everything that he's
asking him to see
and many of us
have likely been
or are in the same
situation as Thomas
you want to believe
you want to have hope
for the future
you want to have
hope of salvation
and new life
and new creation
dawning
but it goes against
everything you've
ever known
you're highly educated
you're sophisticated
and the claims
of the Bible
can seem to be
a bit ridiculous
at times
and yet somewhere
deep within you
this morning
I believe that
Jesus is whispering
your name
somewhere outside
of all the evidence
and all of the logic
and all of the reason
the one who made you
and breathed life
into you
is whispering
your name
he doesn't expect
you to leave
your brain at the door
he doesn't expect
you to have
all of the answers
he's just asking
for a little bit
of faith
a little bit
of trust
lastly
he goes to his
friend Peter
who apparently
does not run
very fast
and if you know
Peter's story
starts with
all of this
religious zeal
that led
to an epic
moral failure
he denied
Jesus three times
even after swearing
on his life
to Jesus
that he never would
this man is
filled with shame
for past mistakes
he goes back
to his life
of fishing
and Jesus
meets him
in the midst
of his shame
and intentionally
brings him
to the same
place
where he denied
Jesus
a charcoal fire
and the same
place
where he denied
Jesus three times
and Jesus
restores Peter
three times
as if to say
it's okay
verse 21
verse 15
when they had
finished breakfast
Jesus said to
Simon Peter
Simon son of
John do you
love me
more than these
he said to
them
yes Lord
you know
that I
love you
feed my
lambs
he said a
second time
Simon son
of John
do you
love me
yes Lord
you know
that I
love you
tend my
sheep
he said
to him
a third
time
Simon son
of John
do you
love me
Peter was
grieved
because he
had said
to him
a third
time
do you
love me
and he
said
Lord
you know
everything
that I
love you
Jesus
said to
him
feed
my
sheep
Jesus
meets
Peter in
the midst
of shame
and regret
and brings
previously
failed
Jesus
calls him
by name
not once
but three
times
as a way
of signaling
that Jesus
is forgiveness
and restoration
goes beyond
all of
Peter's
failures
and many
of us
have been
or likely
are in
the same
situation
we've
blown
it
big
time
we've
made
horrible
decisions
that have
impacted
our lives
and the
ones we
love
we've
ruined
families
we've
destroyed
marriages
we've
messed
up
and we
don't
feel
worthy
of love
and forgiveness
and our
plan
like Peter
is either
to wallow
in shame
and regret
for the
rest of
our lives
or to
try and
pick
ourselves
up by
our
bootstraps
and prove
to everybody
else
that we're
different
and Jesus
wants to
come to
us in
the midst
of our
shame
whether
we're
wallowing
in it
or whether
we're
trying to
work hard
to prove
to others
that we're
worthy
Jesus
is whispering
your name
saying I
don't need
that from
you
my
forgiveness
is free
and it's
because of
what I
have done
not because
of what
you are
going to
do
and I
love
the
hi guys
real quick
no no
okay we're
good
John has
gone out
of his
way
I hope
you've
seen this
morning
to connect
his account
of the
resurrection
to the
garden of
Eden
his point
is not
just about
where you
go when
you die
it's
about
new
creation
breaking
through
right
now
and this
new
creation
isn't just
for the
religiously
inclined
it's for
people like
Mary who
are suffering
with the
realities of
a broken
world
it's for
people like
Thomas
riddled
with
intellectual
doubts
it's for
people like
Peter picking
up the
pieces of
their selfish
decisions
it's for
you and
me
wherever we
find ourselves
out this
morning
John's
point
his
overarching
message of
the
resurrection
is the
has launched
new creation
and we
are invited
to join
in
the question
is do we
hear Jesus
whispering our
name this
morning and
are we ready
for him to
breathe new
life on
us
so we
conclude our
service we're
going to sing
a song the
line is it's
your breath
in our lungs
so we pour
out our
praise
and this
is what
John's
gospel is
all about
it's an
invitation to
receive the
breath of
new creation
life in
our lungs
and to
respond with
praise and
with surrender
to him for
the rest of
our lives
the gospel is
bigger than
we thought
it's more
personal than
we imagined
it's new
creation life
and it's
for you
for your
grief for
your doubts
and your
failures
and today
Jesus is
still breathing
new life
still inviting
us to
receive it
so as we
sing this
song it's
your breath
in our
lungs
I'd invite
that to be
your prayer
you give
life
you are
love
you bring
light
to
the
darkness
you give
hope
you restore
every
heart
that is
broken
great
are you
Lord
you give
life
you are
love
you bring
light
to
the
darkness
you give
hope
you restore
every
heart
that
is
broken
great
are you
Lord
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
we pour
out our
praise
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
to you
only
you give
life
you are
love
you bring
light
to
the
darkness
you give
hope
you restore
every
heart
that is
broken
great
are you
Lord
great
are you
Lord
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
to you
only
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
we pour
out our
praise
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our
praise
to you
only
our hearts will cry
all
all the
earth will
shout your
praise
our hearts
will cry
these bones
will sing
great
are you
Lord
all the earth
will shout
your praise
our hearts
will cry
these bones
will sing
great
are you
Lord
all the earth
will shout
your praise
our hearts
will cry
these bones
will sing
great
are you
Lord
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
to you
only
it's your
breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
our praises
your breath
in our
lungs
so we
pour out
our praise
you
only
great
great are you
Lord
we sing
great are you
Lord
we sing
great are you
Lord
let's keep singing
that this morning
we sing
great are you
you Lord
we sing great are you Lord
great are you Lord
all the earth will shout your praise our hearts will cry these bones will sing great are you Lord
our hearts will cry these bones will sing great are you Lord
all the earth will shout your praise our hearts will sing great are you Lord
all the earth will shout your praise our hearts will cry these bones will sing great are you Lord
it's your bread in our lungs so we pour out our praise we pour out our praise we pour out our praise
it's your bread in our lungs so we pour out our praise we pour out our praise
it's your bread in our lungs so we pour out our praise you only
so in the greek when when Jesus comes to Peter in his shame one thing we can't see in the english is
Jesus says Peter do you agape love me do you love me unconditionally and
Peter says i phileo i brotherly love you
same thing agape phileo and then Jesus
on the third time meets him
with phileo do you brotherly love me
i heard a scholar say this week
it's almost as if Jesus says to Peter if that's all you've got that's where we'll start
and so this morning as we've talked a lot about new creation and where you're at with Jesus maybe
you've just maybe you've just got like a breath of faith i just want you to hear this morning if
that's where you're at then that's where Jesus will start
you don't need to be all the way there you don't need to be over the finish line you just need to be
ready to get up out of your chair
so as we end our service this morning there's gonna be people at the prayer tent
maybe somebody that you came with you want to share what's going on in your life whether it's sorrow
or doubts or shame whatever it might be in your life that you need prayer for or want to work through
just find somebody that looks like they can pray for you and pray with them
and um enjoy the rest of the day as we
keep in mind the hope
of a future resurrection
father we love you we thank you for the empty tomb
for the breath of new creation life
may we leave this place and walk in it
looking for ways to to be the embodiment of the prayer your kingdom come
and your will be done on earth as it is in heaven
in Jesus name i pray amen
so we pour out our praise
so we pour out our praise it's your breath in our lungs
so we pour out our praise we pour out our praise it's your breath in our lungs
So we pour out our praise to you.